Poras Singh

poras.singh301@gmail.com

9850785884

linkedin.com/in/poras-singh

Summary

A python developer with over 2 years of experience with expertise in Django, ORM and HTML/CSS. Additionally, I have worked on Deep Learning and Machine Learning projects. Capable of building entire workflows for features like subscriptions with numerous third-party connectors.

Experience



Python Developer

Creo IT Private Limited

Jan 2022 - Mar 2024 (2 years 3 months)

- Engineered, maintained, and documented RESTful APIs, utilizing AWS Linux servers, resulting in a 40% reduction in server response time and a 25% increase in overall system performance.
- Experimented and documented various deployment strategies which reduced server downtime by 40%
- Improved the project quality by removing deprecated code after upgrading Django version and it's dependencies reducing the risk of code failure by 30%
- · Designed and generated various types pdf documents using HTML/CSS and ORM boosting customer engagement by 25% and also automating various redundant tasks
- Led backend for a chatbot that helped 90% of patients throughout their medical journey with chat retention using MongoDB

Android Developer intern

TWIT Corps

May 2021 - Aug 2021 (4 months)

- Built a real-time chatting app with end to end AES-encrypted messages to lower the risk of eavesdropping
- Gathered requirements from client and researched on the cheapest alternatives to build the app's features which reduced the expenditure by 10%
- Integrated video calling and voice calling features which boosted popularity of the project by 50% among all the board members

Python developer intern

Cloudage Global Services Private Limited.

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020 (4 months)

- Led a team of three to build a web app on Django which helped clients gain edge over their competitors
- · Assisted the UI/UX team in using HTML/CSS with Django which accelerated the project development speed by 1 month
- Mentored new recruits and guided them through the project which enabled a smoother onboarding process and boost productivity by 60%

Education



SHALAKA FOUNDATIONS KEYSTONE SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, PUNE

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering

2018 - 2022

- · Graduated with a CGPA of 9.03
- Granted the post of ACM secretary
- · Vice captain of the football team and co-led the team to semi finals at COEP football tournament
- · Conducted and managed various formal and informal college events

Licenses & Certifications



Deep learning - Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/BNA2PVC74L5Z

Data science - Udemy

UC-0859b290-8aca-4d28-9ebe-0224b7688f7f

Machine Learning - IBM



AWS fundamentals - Coursera

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Django • Machine Learning • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Docker Swarm • Git

Honors & Awards



Performer of the year - SHALAKA FOUNDATIONS KEYSTONE SCHOOL OF **ENGINEERING, PUNE**

Feb 2020

- · Led a band of 3 members and performed a fusion of Bollywood and western music
- · Choreographed dance performances